# SALVADOR JIMÉNEZ NORIEGA

FULL STACK DEVELOPER MERN/JS AND PYTHON

# CONTACT

- (331) 526-2903
- NOJISO@GMAIL.COM
- Q GUADALAJARA, MÉXICO

SJIMENEZ.ME

GITHUB.COM/CHAVUS LINKEDIN.COM/IN/SJIMENEZN

## SKILLS

- Python
- Flask
- Javascript
- HTML/CSS/SASS
- jQuery
- node.js
- Express.js
- React
- MongoDB
- Git/Github
- Heroku
- Vercel
- IBM Cloud
- AWS
- Software QA/Testing
- Agile/Scrum

## **ABOUT**

I love programming and developing applications. For 2 years, I have been developing applications with **Python-Flask and now with Javascript-MERN**. I enjoy the whole process of developing a new application, from the ideation and design to the architecture and development, where I can get creative and be techically challenged.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### FULLSTACK DEVELOPER - PYTHON AND JS/MERN

FREELANCE | MARCH 2019 - CURRENT

- Help businesses turn their paper and manual processes into web applications.
- Build web applications using: Python Flask and Javascript MERN
- Version control and deployment: Git/Github, Heroku, Vercel, IBM Cloud and AWS

## **SOFTWARE QA AND TESTING ENGINEER**

IMPROVING | OCTOBER 2017 - CURRENT

- Successfully define and execute test strategy for a variety of web and mobile projects. Industries: Fintech, Marketing, Law Practice, Education
- Lead some QA/Testing team members: People management activities and technical support.
- Develop test automation framework for web applications using Selenium, Python, Unittest, and Pytest
- Most used tools: Jira/Confluence, Xray, TestRails, Postman
- Familiarized with Software Development Lifecycle and Agile methodologies (Certified Scrum Master)

## **AUTOMATION TEST ENGINEER**

IBM | AUGUST 2010 - ENERO DE 2013

- Defined and automated test processes for IBM tape and HDD storage products in manufacturing for mid- and large-size tape library systems(IBM TS3100/3200, TS4500 and LTO tape drives). Tech stack: Linux and Python
- As Cloud Computing subject matter expert, I promoted and educated employees about CC. I did a one month residency in Shanghai, China to co-author SmartCloud Storage Access Redbook (ISBN:0738439282)

## EDUCACIÓN

JS/MERN FULLSTACK DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP
KODEMIA CODE ACADEMY, MEXICO | 2021

AUTOMATION AND CONTROL - SPECIALIZATION MECHATRONICS ENGINEERING - BACHELOR'S UNIVERSIDAD PANAMERICANA | 2005-2010

#### CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Scrum Master, Scrum Institute, 2019
Design Thinking, IBM, 2016
IBM Cloud, IBM, 2016